Emirhan Kaplan

emskaplann@gmail.com | (929)-405-8405 | New York City, NY Personal Website | LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium | Behance

Full-Stack Web Developer

Full-Stack Web and Cross-Platform Mobile App Developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript. I have a passion for coding since sixth grade, and creating apps from scratch makes me excited about software-engineering. I would love being part of companies with creative cultures, and I am looking forward to contributing my full capacity and experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, React Native, JWT, IBM Watson, Twitter API, Stripe, PostgreSQL, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Semantic-UI React, React-Bootstrap, Native-Base

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Forever 31 - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Demo

A clone of Forever 21 Store that has a much simpler and user-friendly design than the original one.

- Combined, React, Redux, React Semantic-UI and Popmotion(Pose) to design front-end architecture and behaviors.
- Integrated IBM Watson to present an AI that helps the user navigate between pages and sort products.
- Employed Stripe to manage user payments and increase security measures for personal information.
- Programmed Back-End with Ruby on Rails to build an API that serves multiple front-end clients.

ToDo App - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Github Mobile | Demo

A project management tool that allows students to track the progress and completion of their projects.

- Designed web appearance with React-Bootstrap, generating a mobile-first approach.
- Merged reusable React components to React Native, saving time in project completion.
- Implemented JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information.

Word-Tetris - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Github Mobile | Demo

A game that helps individuals to improve their typing skills.

- Used Vanilla JavaScript to create an interactive SPA.
- Incorporated News API, producing fresh words at every new game.
- Operated AsyncStorage in the mobile app to save the user's credentials on each device.

ArtBot - Twitter | Github | Website

A Twitter Bot that tweets historical paintings from WikiArt's most viewed category four times in a day.

- Used Heroku for storing images temporarily enough to posting tweets.
- Utilized <u>Clockwork Gem</u> to create a server that runs jobs automatically by itself in the background.

EXPERIENCE

Server, Cappy Food Corp., Staten Island, NY

September 2019 - Present

- Ensured optimal guest experience by seating guests, taking orders, serving dishes and removing dinnerware promptly and with a positive attitude.
- Negotiated and resolved customer concerns.
- Consistently achieved above 20% charge tip percentage, demonstrating skills providing quality customer service.

Apprentice Optician, Berrak Optical Shop, Istanbul, Turkey

May 2018 - September 2018

- Arranged and maintained displays of optical merchandise.
- Assisted clients in selecting frames according to style and color, and ensured that frames are coordinated with facial and eye measurements and optical prescriptions.
- Heated, shaped or bent plastic or metal frames to adjust eyeglasses to fit clients, using tools and hands.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, U.S.

September 2019 - December 2019

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript curriculum.

Prof. Dr. Mumtaz Turhan Social Sciences High-School, Istanbul, Turkey High School Diploma

August 2015 - June 2019